<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog ✍️ on Analyst</title>
    <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog ✍️ on Analyst</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:42:21 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Game Over</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2022/02/jigsaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:42:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2022/02/jigsaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One sunny 😎 day I came to a coworking office very early in the morning. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to kick it off with a freshly brewed coffee which we never had, so, I had to go with an instant substitute. Ugh 😣! I was hoping to savour my disgust meditating over the Feedly recents, when I noticed that I was not the only lark that day. Mark, a freelance designer who happened to be a huge fan of Assassin&amp;rsquo;s Creed games (just like me), was sitting in the corner of the shared kitchen with his laptop, looking so gloomy that I was sorry I didn&amp;rsquo;t take my ☔️ with me. When I&amp;rsquo;ve forced the last sip of that potion inside, I wished him good morning and headed to my working nest. He didn&amp;rsquo;t respond though, which was weird, since he usually was very friendly. I thought he needed some time on his own and was about to leave the kitchen when suddenly he hailed me. Long story short, he seemed to get himself a virus and didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to get rid of it. He seemed scared, since lots of important files were encrypted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Once There Lived Admin</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2022/02/once-there-lived-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 11:42:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2022/02/once-there-lived-admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hey, ps! Would like you to hear a fairy tale? I am sure that you do! It all happened not long long time ago and not in a galaxy far far away&amp;hellip; . Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that in the J.Rowling&amp;rsquo;s universe there were cybersecurity specialists as well and Hogwarts had a real website in the Internet. Funky idea! 💡&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A very hard-working girl, let&amp;rsquo;s call her Rachel (yeah, Rachel 😉) was sitting at her table, working as usual when she suddenly saw her phone vibrating nearby. She picked up the phone, hoping that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a spam. Indeed it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. That was her colleague, asking if she is interested in a little side project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord of the Apple: The Return of the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/08/lord-of-the-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:18:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/08/lord-of-the-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📆 &lt;code&gt;22/08/2021&lt;/code&gt; , &lt;em&gt;Sunday&lt;/em&gt;, ☁️&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🕰 &lt;code&gt;11:21 AM&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a cloudy Sunday morning. I was sleeping peacefully till 8:45 AM when my daughter started crawling all over me and my husband asking wether I am awake already&amp;hellip; . Well, now I am, darling, many thanks 🤦🏻‍♀️! After having a delicious breakfast (eggplants with home-made tomato sauce, yummy 😋) and getting the kitchen back to the clean state (it&amp;rsquo;s very hard to keep it that way), I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to finally repair my little old fellow iPhone 7. Several weeks ago I went on vocation to Cyprus and broke the rare camera glass and the screen as well, because I somehow managed to drop the phone on the pavement 3 ❗️times! To be honest, these were not the first times when my iPhone met some surface harder than my palm, so it&amp;rsquo;s a miracle this had not happened before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Carry Out MockInv&#39;estigation. Part 1</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/06/toy-story-pd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:18:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/06/toy-story-pd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;❗SPOILER ALERT!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;📆 &lt;code&gt;16/06/2021&lt;/code&gt; , &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🕰 &lt;code&gt;09:21 PM&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was a very sunny day and a very nice a long walk that my daughter and I had before lunch. I feel uplifted because there is finally enough sun and green grass in my life! Unfortunately, no coffee today, since we don&amp;rsquo;t have BonAcqua, which might be not the best for drinking, but is indeed one of the best to prepare coffee (quoting my husband).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Carry Out MockInv&#39;estigation. Part 2</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/06/magnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:18:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/06/magnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📆 &lt;code&gt;16/06/2021&lt;/code&gt; , &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🕰 &lt;code&gt;09:21 PM&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I had a 7-day license of Magnet AXIOM and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try this tool and compare it with others that I had. In 2021 May-June Magnet held a great event of a great value - Magnet SUMMIT with lots of very useful webinars and workshops. One of them was a case study using Magnet. I am going to follow these steps and study another way to solve a crime.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Got Started With ARM</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-got-started-with-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:42:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-got-started-with-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📆 &lt;code&gt;Friday, 12th of March, 202&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;⏰ &lt;code&gt;09:00&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;☀️ &lt;em&gt;It was a very deceptively sunny morning, children laughing and squeaking merrily. When I closed my eyes I could almoust believe it was late spring or summer&amp;hellip;. And the soul was filling with joy and inspiration. But unfortunately the temperature was too low (-10 ❄️ ⛄️  if you believe Yandex) and going for a outside-working-day was impossible 😔.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am finishing my cup of coffee ☕️ , my husband working in the adjacent room and my daughter playing with her new toys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Got Started With AWS</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-got-started-with-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 11:42:21 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-got-started-with-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this blog post I am exploring AWS services (EC2). I am currently using a Free Tier license and I am trying to learn how to use. Why? Well, knowing AWS seems to be a very useful skill on the market. And the second reason for that is that I used to have different VMs that cosumed too much memory (HDD and RAM). Now I am also using M1 MacBook Pro and that&amp;rsquo;s why having so many VMs locally is impossible since there are only some Linux and Windows 10 Machines available for ARM platform. Besides, I&amp;rsquo;ve notices that I don&amp;rsquo;t really use them much so having 60 GB of space occupied for occasional usage is weird. Everything speaks in the favour of AWS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Have Built My Lab</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-have-built-my-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 22:14:08 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/how-i-have-built-my-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One late evening when my eyes were so difficult to keep open, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to setup a Windows Lab on my M1 Mac. Long story short, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make Autopsy work as expected and that&amp;rsquo;s why I had to waste my time on this task&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x1f4c6; &lt;code&gt;01/03/2021&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x23f0; &lt;code&gt;22:17&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, I had to sign up to Microsoft Insider Program &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windowsinsiderpreviewARM64?wa=wsignin1.0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It was free and I signed up. Then, I&amp;rsquo;ve installed Parallels from &lt;a href=&#34;https://b2b.parallels.com/apple-silicon&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; using &amp;ldquo;Try technical preview&amp;rdquo; option that was available at this point in time. Also, at this point of time a free activation key &amp;#x1f511; was available for Parallels (thank you 🙏 so much, guys, for this) &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.parallels.com/desktop/beta?_ga=2.154508411.2118090463.1614625046-817269375.1614625046&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. During installation process I was a little bewildered by the question about the use purpose of this software&amp;hellip; Gaming or ordinary use (text editing, web-browsing etc). I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen &amp;ldquo;Gaming&amp;rdquo; since I presume Autopsy and software alike do consume much power. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this option changes the performance or it&amp;rsquo;s rather some survey. Anyway. After all that everything worked like a charm. But I still have not tried installing autopsy&amp;hellip; So, let&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spoiling Dr Evil</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/spoiling-dr-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:14:41 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2021/03/spoiling-dr-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to solve a puzzle per week just to keep myself &amp;ldquo;forensically fit&amp;rdquo;. This is my case study of Dr.Evil case (spoiler alert &amp;#x26a0;&amp;#xfe0f;). If you wish to solve it yourself, don&amp;rsquo;t read this blog post!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-objectives&#34;&gt;Case Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On &lt;code&gt;09/20/04&lt;/code&gt; , a Dell CPi notebook computer, serial # &lt;code&gt;VLQLW&lt;/code&gt;, was found abandoned along with a wireless PCMCIA card and an external homemade 802.11b antennae. It is suspected that this computer was used for hacking purposes, although cannot be tied to a hacking suspect, G=r=e=g S=c=h=a=r=d=t. (The equal signs are just to prevent web crawlers from indexing this name; there are no equal signs in the image files.) &lt;code&gt;Schardt&lt;/code&gt; also goes by the online nickname of &lt;code&gt;“Mr. Evil”&lt;/code&gt; and some of his associates have said that he would park his vehicle within range of Wireless Access Points (like Starbucks and other T-Mobile Hotspots) where he would then intercept internet traffic, attempting to get credit card numbers, usernames &amp;amp; passwords.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Few Good Bits</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/10/a-few-good-bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 18:53:48 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/10/a-few-good-bits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently have had a severe poisoning (I only hope it&amp;rsquo;s not the rotavirus &amp;#x1f628;) and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent one evening and one day barely moving. Even now, almost two days have passed, but I still feel a little nauseous. But I&amp;rsquo;m not that bad enough now to refresh and learn some assembly (it&amp;rsquo;s always a good medicine for the wicked &amp;#x1f638;). The following chain of thoughts was cut from &lt;a href=&#34;https://bakerst221b.com/docs/articles/fundamentals/reveng/assembly-operations&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article once the critical mass of text for &lt;code&gt;SHL/SHR&lt;/code&gt; has exceeded its maximum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Radare2</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-met-radare2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 10:40:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-met-radare2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;📆 &lt;code&gt;24/09/2020&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🕰 &lt;code&gt;7:00&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;What a nice morning! And it&amp;rsquo;s so great to be woken up by a high-pitched cry in the ear&amp;hellip; Well, after giving my daughter her breakfast and doing all the neccessary hygine procedures for us both, I left her by my side on the development carpet, so that I could develop myself&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🛠  &lt;strong&gt;Environment and Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: macOS Catalina 10.15.6 (19G2021) + pyenv 1.2.20 + Python 3.8.5 + Visual Code Version: 1.49.1, VBox Version 6.1.12 r139181 (Qt5.6.3) + Kali Linux + radare2 4.6.0-git 25077 @ linux-x86-64 git.4.4.0-749-g2a0d8fbe5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Fragment Injection</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-fought-fragment-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 22:26:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-fought-fragment-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moscow has again become Mordor-like, the Sun is starting to make its heat more official rather than genuine because it&amp;rsquo;s getting desperately cold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Android Studio 4.0.1, built on June, 25, 2020 (Runtime version: 1.8.0_242-release-1644-b3-6222593 X86_64, VM: OpenJDK 64-bit Server VM by JetbBrains s.r.o.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05:35 am&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x1f62a; Even though I went to sleep too late yesterday (due to my wushu 🧎🏽‍♀️practice and a bath I had to take to help my muscles overcome the shock of such an unusual physical activity after almoust a year of turning into a very pretty and round stump of a tree and covering with moss after several months of coronavirus-driven self-isolation), I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep my eyes shut because I was so obsesed by and absorbed with the idea of my new project: Android Exploiter. So, I tried to fall asleep (just for appearance&amp;rsquo;s sake) for about 40 minutes, but since my husband has already gotten up and my little three-year old daughter as well, seemed no use to insist. So, I got up and was about to go to the kitchen, but was stuck by my laptop once again&amp;hellip; Why this stupid application is not running? What am I doing wrong. &amp;#x1f621; That day I&amp;rsquo;ve hardly left the table&amp;hellip;👩🏽‍💻&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Predator</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/07/analytic-protiv-khishnika/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 14:39:39 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/07/analytic-protiv-khishnika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Ничего так, тепло.*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Где-то в тёмном-тёмном лесу, среди высоких старых деревьев, притаившись в кустах выжидают свою жертву хищники. И даже несмотря на то, что они могут быть не такими страшными, как товарищ из фильма, тем не менее могут принести немало проблем. Мало кто воспринимает интернет как &amp;ldquo;страшный и таинственный лес&amp;rdquo;, но тем не менее в какой-то степени так и есть. И хищники там тоже есть, и поверьте мне, они не такие милые как пушистое создание на картинке.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undesirable Mail</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/07/undesirable-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 14:19:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/07/undesirable-mail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warm and cloudy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Open me! I am a payment order! I am important, I swear!&amp;rdquo;, - some RTF-file was yelling. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting any bills so this slyboots did not maim my poor little laptop. Phew ! Lucky me! But since this was a social engineering attack (not very crafty but still), someone less concerned with his or her safety could have opened it and cause him- or herself a lot of trouble. What I am trying to say (very inarticulately ) is that simply opening a small RTF document could result in absolute disaster for your machine! In this post I am telling the story how exactly does it happen&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Dot NET Confuser</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/04/dot-net-confuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 14:45:49 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2018/04/dot-net-confuser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Вторник, прохладно, как будто вот-вот пойдет дождь, но нет&amp;hellip;. Приятно бывает встретиться лицом к лицу с сильным противником, потому что именно в такие моменты, после таких &amp;ldquo;битв&amp;rdquo;, становишься сильнее. Прошедший вторник оказался настоящим вызовом для моей смекалки. Ну здравствуй, Confuser! Очень надеюсь, что вам понравится статья точно так же, как мне понравилось ковырять этот код и писать эту скромную статью. Все началось одним облачным утром&amp;hellip;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Среда&lt;/strong&gt;: VBox Version 5.2.12 r122591 (Qt5.6.2), Win7x64 SP1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Met Hugo</title>
      <link>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-met-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 13:45:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bakerst221b.com/docs/blog/2020/09/how-i-met-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time when I was desperately trying to become a web programmer (those wonderful days of naïve curiosity🤦‍♀️). I’ve even attended a course (which turned out to be useless&amp;hellip; If only I knew back then, that I could better learn it all for free on my own. Alas!😭).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I created some repulsive HTML pages with a crappy JavaScript🤮. I remember one of the first projects: a page with a binary converter🙌. Some time later, when I’ve found a job as a C# programmer, I’ve met the beauty of asp.net (&lt;a href=&#34;http://asp.net/&#34;&gt;http://asp.net/&lt;/a&gt;) and realized I don’t have to deal with php (which my soft mental constitution could not bear 👸) and that I don’t always have to write  websites from scratch and what’s more, to develop the design for it myself&amp;hellip; After I’ve started my career in InfoSec field, I’ve stumbled upon a task which I managed to solve with .net web engine and my beloved C#. But the site was as usual, not very pretty, to say the least&amp;hellip; Actually, I’ve tried to copy VisualStudio styles and managed partly, but it was like a 5 year old trying to copy Tician. Almost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
